<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arthur Rocha</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Arthur Rocha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zn-Hans</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 12:03:06 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Xkcd to Make Density Plots</title>
      <link>/post/2019-04-24-using-xkcd-to-make-density-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 12:03:06 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-04-24-using-xkcd-to-make-density-plots/</guid>
      <description>So, I’ve always been interesting in the “xkcd type” of figures only because IT’S FUN.
My goal here is to make density plots of the most common probability functions using the xkcd style.
First of all, we will need to load these packages:library(xkcd)library(dplyr)library(ggplot2)Now, we do a function using the ggplot2 sintax to make the plot. Note that we need calculate the axes ranges and apply “jitter” to x and y to create a hand-drawn effect in the line.xkcd_density = function(x,y){# Calcule the axis rangexrange = range(x)yrange = range(y)# Plot line type + jitterqplot(jitter(x),jitter(y),geom = &amp;quot;blank&amp;quot;)+geom_line(linetype = 1,size=1.5)+theme_xkcd()+xkcdaxis(xrange,yrange)+xlab(&amp;quot;&amp;quot;)+ylab(&amp;quot;&amp;quot;)}Ploting the standart normal (0,1) density.x = seq(-3,3,by=.1)y = dnorm(x,mean=0,sd=1)xkcd_density(x,y)Ploting the Chi square (df = 3) desity.x = c(0,seq(0.1,10,by=.1))y = c(0,dchisq(x[-1],df=3))xkcd_density(x,y)There you have! A nice looking (sort of) xkcd density plot!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How (and why) I made this blog</title>
      <link>/post/how-and-why-i-made-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-and-why-i-made-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a long (kind of) time since I start to formulate the idea for a blog to share my statistical/analytical stuff, more precisely since I was in the second year of my bachelor degree (2016). Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot (in multiple fields), so, finally I&amp;rsquo;m able to make this thing happen!
As a statistician, I was molded in the R/S-plus world, so the most convenient way to make this site (that I&amp;rsquo;ve found) was using the bookdown package for R, wich is a really great tool to build blogs like this, based in the Hugo framework, and have a nice integration with the R-studio IDE.
For this blog I&amp;rsquo;m using the AllinOne theme by Orianna with some modifications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>